Olamijulo Taiwo

Mobile Developer

Address Surulere, 101283

Phone 09068673491

E-mail taiwoolamijulo.to@gmail.com

I'm a software developer with 6 years experience, 4 years in flutter. I'm proficient with working with several state management tools and libraries in flutter examples include - Provider, getx, riverpod, google maps api, google cloud message, cloud firestore, socket.io and many more. I pride my self in writing clean properly architected code using MVVM, Domain Driven Design(DDD), Test Driven Design(TDD) design patterns/ Architecture. I'm very good at processing information which aids me when I read documentation on a new subject and allows me to learn and improve very quickly. I'm very driven and passionate about what I do and this extends to my professionalism in the work place as I put in a lot of effort and time into getting work done.

Skills

Flutter

Google Cloud Platform

Firebase Cloud Messaging

OneSignal

RiverPod

Provider

GetX

Google Maps

Socket.io

Work History

2022-02 - Current

Mobile Application Developer | Flutter

Sterling Bank, Lagos Island

- Worked with a team of 7 mobile developers to develop an upgraded version of the core bank app (OneBank).
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define, design and ship new features.
- Built code using specified technology to articulate status and user stories.
- Focused on continuous improvement by keeping up-to-date on latest Android and iOS developments and trends and presenting for architectural review.
- Clean Architecture was the chosen architect pattern used

- Implemented rapid prototypes to get products to market quickly.
- Sized and estimated software changes and features based upon functional and technical experience.
- Riverpod was the chosen state management tool for the project.
- implemented push notifications using OneSignal.
- Engaged in sprint planning which was managed on Azure DevOps.
- Engaged in Scrum following Agile methodology.
- wrote unit tests to test the integrity of my methods.

2020-10 - 2022-01 Mobile Application Developer | Flutter

Techgrata, Lagos Island

- Single handedly developed Company's Mobile Application (Olage) to allow people to book vehicles for delivery of different types of use cases using Flutter.
- Managing and updating Mobile Application (Olage).
- Implemented Google Maps and Google Addresses for the purpose of navigation.
- Implemented rapid prototypes to get products to market quickly.
- Sized and estimated software changes and features based upon functional and technical experience.
- implemented Socket.lo for the in app chat messaging.
- MVVM architecture was the preferred architecture for this project.
- Provider was the state management of choice for the project.
- Implemented firebase push notification for the handling of vehicle request, chat messages and driver response on the app.
- wrote unit tests to test the integrity of my methods.
- worked with trello to manage tasks.

2022-01 - 2023-03 Mobile Application Developer | Flutter (Contract)

TGap, Surulere

- Developed Client's Mobile Application (TGap) to allow people pay bills.
- Managing and updating Mobile Application (TGap).
- structured the app using MVVM architecture.
- Getx was the chosen state management tool for the project.
- Implemented text message and email notification using sendinblue service.
- Implemented google admob for monetization.
- Implemented flutterwave payment gateway for handling payments

2022-06 - 2022-12 Mobile Application Developer | Flutter (Contract)

Smarta App, Ikorodu

- Developed Clients app (Smarta Water App) to allow people to book vehicles for delivery of different types of water using Flutter.
- Managing and updating Mobile Application(Smarta Water App).
- Implemented google maps and google addresses.
- Implemented rapid prototypes to get products to market quickly.
- Implemented socket.io for the in app chat messaging.
- MVVM architecture was the chosen architecture used.
- Getx was the chosen state management tool for the project.

- Implemented firebase push notification for the handling of vehicle request and driver response on the app.
- Implemented flutterwave payment gateway to receive payment.
- wrote unit tests to test the integrity of my methods.

Education

2017-04 - 2020-06 Professional Diploma: Software Engineering

NIIT - Nigeria